MOHAMED SAID

SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER - SDET (CTFL)

MUHAMMEDSAIDSYED 215@GMAIL.COM | +201155265518



SUMMARY

A professional Software Test Engineer with more than 4 years of Experience who has worked in a variety of business domains and industries implementing high knowledge and qualifications in Manual, Mobile, API and Automation software testing techniques. who is an ISTQB certified with a bachelor degree of Science.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Manual Testing (Test Planning, Test Design Techniques, localization and globalization testing, Payment Testing and Issue Reporting), Programming Languages (Java, JavaScript and Python), CI & CD (Git, GitHub, Gitlab, Docker, Jenkins), Management tools (Azure Devops, Jira, Zephyr Scale), Web UI and mobile Automation Testing tools and Frameworks (Selenium, Allure, Cucumber, Appium, Espresso, Playwright, Cypress, Katalon), Api Testing with Postman, SoapUI and REST Assured, Visual Testing with AppliTools, Developing and Testing Applications with Flutter (Advanced), Performance Testing with Jmeter.

EXPERIENCE

National Technology | Software Test Engineer | Sep 2022 - Now | Cairo, Egypt | Full-time

- ✓ Designed and executed advanced test cases in the Laboratory Information System of The Company (LDM).
- ✔ Wrote Detailed Defect Reports.
- ✓ Used Oracle Database to treat Backend Data.
- ✓ Tested APIs with Postman and wrote Advanced Test cases.
- ✓ Tested the ability of the LDM (LIS) to Integrate with other Systems (Analyzers, Hospitals, Authorities, Service's Providers).
- ✔ Created Microsoft Services and made customized configurations.
- ✓ Used Services to Send and Receive Date From Clients and Servers.
- ✓ Acquired great experience in HL7 protocol.
- ✔ Wrote detailed documents about all external integration cycles.
- ✓ Used Remote Desktop Organizer, AnyDisc and Zoho.

Donet | Software Test Engineer | June 2021 – Now | Cairo, Egypt | Part-time

- ✓ Made Extensive localization and globalization testing for many live mobile applications.
- ✓ Performed Payment testing with many payments and transactions methods.
- ✓ Completed Advanced Analytics Testing.

Macro Group Pharmaceuticals | QA Engineer | June 2022 - Dec 2022 | Cairo, Egypt | Full-time Military Service | Quality Soldier | May 2020 - June 2021 | Cairo, Egypt | Full-time Pepsico Egypt | Quality Specialist | Sep 2019 - May 2020 | Cairo, Egypt | Full-time

EDUCATION

Faculty of Science Ain shams university | Cairo, Egypt | 2015-2019

The Bachelor of Science (B.Sc. degree)

Certificates

- 1. ISTQB Foundation Level(CTFL), Credential ID 230524014 May-2023
- 2. Cypress Path, <u>Test Automation University</u> Dec 2023
- 3. Playwright Path, <u>Test Automation University</u> Nov 2023
- 4. Java Mobile Path, <u>Test Automation University</u> Nov 2023
- 5. Java Web UI Path, Test Automation University Oct 2023
- 6. Codeless Testing Path, Test Automation University Sep 2023
- 7. Java API Path, <u>Test Automation University</u> Aug 2023
- 8. <u>Java (Basic)</u> Certificate Hackerrank Aug 2023
- 9. SQL Certificate SoloLearn Jan 2022
- 10. Java Certificate SoloLearn Sep 2022
- 11. Fundamentals of Digital Marketing[Google] Feb 2023
- 12. Foundation of Digital Marketing[Coursera] Mar 2023
- 13. Front End Development[Udacity] Aug 2021
- 14. Data Analyst[Udacity] Sep 2018

Courses

- ★ Programming With Java[Barmej.com] Dec 2018
- ★ Become an Excel Guru[Udemy] June 2018
- ★ OracleSQL-A complete Introduction[Udemy] July 2018
- ★ Intro to Deep Learning[Kaggle] May 2022.
- ★ Selenium WebDriver from Foundations to Framework[InArabic] Aug 2023
- ★ Completed All Marketing, Financial And Communication [Hp Life] Courses 2023.
- ★ Deep Learning Engineer [MaharaTech) May 2022.
- ★ <u>DataAnalysis</u>[MaharaTech] Feb 2023.

Achievements

- 1.Java Code Preparation HackerRank Aug 2023
- 2.30 Days of Code-HackerRank-Aug2023
- 3. Created [iTeam] application to enhance teamwork with Flutter and Firebase.
- 4. Passed LinkedIn Skill Assessments (Python Machine Learning Ms Excel)

Volunteering

One Million Arab Coders, Udacity | Data Analysis Tutor | Jun- Nov 2018

Helped the Arab students to write advanced SQL scripts to solve difficult challenges.

LANGUAGES

Arabic (Mother tongue)
English (Advanced)
German (Intermediate)